Okay. So I'm delighted to introduce,
好的。所以我很高兴地介绍，
um, our first lot of invited speakers.
嗯，我们的第一批受邀演讲者。
And so we're gonna have two invited speakers, um, today.
所以我们今天要邀请两位发言者，嗯。
So starting off, um,
首先，嗯，
we go and have Ashish Vaswani who's gonna be
我们去和Ashish Vaswani一起去
talking about self attention for generative models and in particular,
谈论生成模型的自我关注，特别是
um, we'll introduce some of the work on
嗯，我们将介绍一些工作
transformers that he is well-known for along with his colleagues.
变形金刚，他和他的同事一起出名。
Um and then as a sort of, um,
嗯，然后作为一种，嗯，
a special edition then we're also going to have
特别版然后我们也将有
Anna Huang talking about some applications of this work.
Anna Huang谈到了这项工作的一些应用。
There are actually at least a couple of people in the class who are
实际上班上至少有几个人
actually interested in music applications.
实际上对音乐应用感兴趣。
So this will be your one chance in the course to see music applications of deep learning.
因此，这将是您在课程中看到深度学习的音乐应用的一次机会。
Okay, um, so I'll hand it over to Ashish.
好的，嗯，所以我会把它交给Ashish。
Thanks, Chris and, uh, thanks, Evie.
谢谢，克里斯，呃，谢谢，伊维。
Uh, Anna is actually here to make the class less dull.
呃，安娜实际上是为了让课堂变得不那么沉闷。
So [LAUGHTER] she's the highlight on this one.
所以[笑声]她是这一个的亮点。
So uh, so, uh, hi everyone.
所以，呃，大家好。
Um, um, uh excited to be here.
嗯，嗯，很高兴能来到这里。
This is a very large class.
这是一个非常大的课程。
Uh, first invited speaker,
呃，首先邀请了演讲者，
no pressure, so hopefully this will all go well.
没有压力，所以希望这一切都会顺利进行。
Uh, so yes, so the talk is going to be about, uh, self attention.
呃，是的，所以谈论将是关于，呃，自我关注。
Um, and so the purpose is,
嗯，所以目的是，
is not going to be just to talk about a particular model, but, as,
不仅仅是谈论一个特定的模型，但是，作为，
as, as, as empiricists and, and,
就像经验主义者一样，和
like, well, I'm an empiricist and I
就像，嗯，我是一名经验主义者和我
consume machine learning to apply it to various tasks.
消耗机器学习将其应用于各种任务。
And, and, and, well, starting point always is to ask this question, you know,
而且，而且，好吧，起点总是提出这个问题，你知道，
what are the- what's the structure in
什么是 - 结构是什么
my dataset or what are the symmetries in my dataset,
我的数据集或我的数据集中的对称性是什么，
and is there a model that exists that that's a very good- that,
是否存在一个非常好的模型 -
that has the inductive biases to model these properties that exist in my dataset.
具有归纳偏差来模拟我的数据集中存在的这些属性。
So hopefully, over the course of this, uh,
所以希望，在这个过程中，呃，
this, this lecture Anna and I will convince you that, uh,
这个，安娜和我这个讲座会说服你，呃，
self attention indeed does have some- has
自我注意确实有一些
the ability models and inductive biases that
能力模型和归纳偏见
potentially could be useful for the problems that you care about.
可能对您关心的问题有用。
Um, so, um, this talk is going to be our learning representations primarily of,
嗯，所以，嗯，这次演讲将主要是我们的学习陈述，
uh, variable length data where we have images but,
呃，我们有图像的可变长度数据，但是，
uh, most of it is going to be variable length data.
呃，大部分都是可变长度的数据。
And, uh, and, and,
而且，呃，和，和，
and all of us care about this problem because we- in
我们所有人都关心这个问题，因为我们在
deep learning, and deep learning is all about representation learning.
深度学习，深度学习就是表征学习。
And if- and building the right tools for learning representations as,
如果 - 并建立正确的学习表示工具，
as, as, as sort of- is an important factor in,
因为，作为一种重要因素，
in achieving empirical success.
实现经验成功。
Um, now, uh, the models of choice,
嗯，现在，呃，选择的模型，
the primary workhorse for
主要的主力
perhaps even now and or up to this point had been recurrent neural networks.
或许甚至现在和/或到目前为止都是反复出现的神经网络。
Um, um, how, how many people here are familiar with RNNs?
嗯，嗯，怎么样，这里有多少人熟悉RNN？
[LAUGHTER] Okay.
[大笑]好的。
So definitely up to this point,
所以到目前为止，
the primary workhorse have been recurrent neural networks,
主要的主力是反复神经网络，
and some of the more, uh, some, uh,
还有一些，呃，一些，呃，
some gated variants that explicitly add multiplicative interactions like LSTMs,
一些门控变体，明确添加乘法交互，如LSTMs，
they also, they also have mechanisms that allow for better gradient transfer.
他们还有一些机制可以实现更好的梯度转移。
And some recent variants like gated, uh,
最近的一些变种，如门控，呃，
recurrent units that are simplification,
简化的经常性单位，
they're kind of the- they're- they dominate this, this recurrent landscape.
他们是那种 - 他们 - 他们在这个经常性的景观中占主导地位。
Um, and typically how did recurrent neural networks, uh,
嗯，通常神经网络怎么回事，呃，
learn or, um, produce representations?
学习或者，嗯，制作陈述？
They consume a string or a sentence, um,
他们消耗一串或一句话，嗯，
even an image, imagine, you know,
即使是图像，想象一下，你知道，
in a particular- in sequentially and, uh, at each,
在一个特定的顺序和呃，每个，
at each, uh, position,
在每个，呃，位置，
at each timestep they produce, they produce a,
在他们生产的每个时间步，他们生产，
a continuous representation that's
一个连续的表示
summarization of, of everything that they've actually crunched through.
他们实际上已经完成的所有事情的总结。
Um, now, so in, in, in the,
嗯，现在，所以，在，在，
in the realm of large data, uh,
在大数据领域，呃，
par- having parallel models is,
平行模型是，
is quite, is quite beneficial.
非常，非常有益。
In fact, I was actually reading Oliver Selfridge.
事实上，我实际上正在读奥利弗塞尔弗里奇。
Uh, he was a,
呃，他是，
he was a professor at MIT and, uh, he had this,
他是麻省理工学院的教授，呃，他有这个，
uh, sorry, he wrote the precursor to deep nets its it's called Pandemoniums.
呃，对不起，他写了深网的前兆，它叫做Pandemoniums。
I would recommend everybody to read it.
我建议大家阅读。
And he has this fascinating note that, you know,
他有这个引人入胜的说明，你知道，
if you give me more parallel computation,
如果你给我更多的并行计算，
I'll just add more data and make it slower.
我只会添加更多数据并使其变慢。
So you can consume more data.
所以你可以消耗更多的数据。
Um, and, and recurrence, uh, recurrence sort of just by construction, um,
嗯，又复发，呃，复发只是建筑，嗯，
limits parallelization because you have to,
限制并行化，因为你必须，
you have to wait until- your wait un-
你必须等到 - 等你没有 -
for a particular time point to produce a representation.
在特定时间点产生表示。
Um, but if there's any questions,
嗯，但如果有任何问题，
please raise your hands, I'll
请举手，我会
hopefully look around and, and,
希望环顾四周，并且，
uh, be able to attend to your question.
呃，能够处理你的问题。
Um, and again, and, and now because we're actually producing these representations,
嗯，又一次，而且，现在因为我们实际上正在制作这些表示，
we're sort of summarizing,
我们总结一下，
you know, if you want to pass information,
你知道，如果你想传递信息，
if you want to pass co-reference information,
如果你想传递共同参考信息，
then we kind of have to shove all of this inside
那么我们就必须把所有这些都推到里面
this fixed size vector, so it could potentially be difficult to model.
这个固定大小的矢量，因此可能很难建模。
And, uh, while they have been successful in language, uh,
而且，呃，虽然他们在语言上取得了成功，呃，
explicit they don't have- the architecture
明确他们没有 - 建筑
doesn't have a very clear explicit way to model hierarchy which is,
没有非常明确的模型层次结构的明确方式，
which is something that's very important in language.
这在语言中非常重要。
Um, now, um, so they have been devin- it has been excellent work of,
嗯，现在，嗯，所以他们一直在开发 - 这是一项出色的工作，
a precursor to self attention that actually surmounted some of these difficulties.
实际上克服了其中一些困难的自我关注的先兆。
And what were these difficulties basically is a convolutional sequence models
这些困难主要是卷积序列模型
where you have these limited receptive field convolutions that,
在那里你有这些有限的接受场卷积，
again, consumed the sentence now not,
再次，现在没有消耗这句话，
not sequentially but in depth.
不是顺序而是深入。
And they produce representations for every-
他们为每个人制作陈述 -
they produce representations of your variable length sequences.
它们产生可变长度序列的表示。
Um, and, uh, they're trivial to
嗯，呃，他们很琐碎
parallelize because you can apply these convolutions simultaneously at every position.
并行化，因为您可以在每个位置同时应用这些卷积。
Each layer is trivial to parallelize.
每层都很容易并行化。
Uh, the, the, the serial dependencies are only in the number of layers.
呃，系列依赖关系仅在层数上。
Um, you can get, uh,
嗯，你可以得到，呃，
you can- you can get
你可以 - 你可以得到
these local dependencies efficiently because that a single application of
这些本地依赖有效，因为单个应用程序
a convolution can consume all the information inside its local receptive field.
卷积可以消耗其本地感受域内的所有信息。
Um, now if you want to have
嗯，现在如果你想拥有
these really long distance interactions while you
这些真正的长距离互动，而你
don't have to pass through a linear number of steps,
不必通过线性数量的步骤，
you still because these,
你还是因为这些，
because these receptive fields are local you might need something like linear
因为这些感受野是本地的，你可能需要线性的东西
and depth or logarithmic if you're doing something like dilated convolutions.
如果你正在做扩张卷积之类的东西，那就是深度或对数。
So there's still need- the number of layers that are needed are
所以仍然需要 - 所需的层数
still a function of the length of the of, of your string.
仍然是你的字符串的长度的函数。
Uh, but they're a great development and they
呃，但他们是一个伟大的发展和他们
actually pushed a lot of research like WaveRNN, for example,
实际上推动了很多像WaveRNN这样的研究，例如，
is a classic sort of success story of
是一个经典的成功故事
convolutio- convolutional sequence models even by net.
卷积 - 卷积序列模型甚至网络。
Um, now, so far attention has been like one of the most important components,
嗯，现在，到目前为止，注意力一直是最重要的组成部分之一，
the sort of content-based,
基于内容的那种，
you know, memory retrieval mechanism.
你知道，记忆检索机制。
And it's content-based because you have your decoder that attends to all this content,
它是基于内容的，因为你的解码器可以满足所有这些内容，
that's your encoder and then just sort of decides what to wha- what,
这是你的编码器然后只是决定什么，什么，
what information to absorb based on how similar
根据相似程度吸收哪些信息
this content is to every position in the memory.
这个内容是记忆中的每个位置。
So this has been a very critical mechanism in,
所以这是一个非常关键的机制，
uh, in neural machine translation.
呃，在神经机器翻译中。
So now the question that we asked was, like, why,
所以现在我们问的问题是，为什么，
why not just use attention for representations and, uh,
为什么不把注意力用于表达，呃，
now here's what sort of a rough framework of this,
现在这是一个粗略的框架，
this representation mechanism would look like, uh,
这种表示机制看起来像，呃，
the way- just sort of repeating what attention is essentially.
方式 - 只是重复注意力本质上。
Now imagine you have- you want to represent the word,
现在想象你有 - 你想代表这个词，
re-represent the word representing, you want to construct its new representation.
重新表示单词表示，你想构建它的新表示。
And then first, uh, you, you attend or you,
然后首先，呃，你，你参加或者你，
you compare yourself, you compare your content,
你比较自己，比较你的内容，
and in the beginning it could just be a word embedding.
而在一开始它可能只是一个嵌入的单词。
Your compare content with all your words, and with all,
您与所有单词以及所有单词的比较内容，
with all the embeddings and based on these,
所有的嵌入和基于这些，
based on these compatibilities or these comparisons,
基于这些兼容性或这些比较，
you produce, uh, you produce a weighted combination of your entire neighborhood,
你生产，呃，你产生了整个社区的加权组合，
and based on that weighted combination you,
并根据加权组合你，
you summarize all that information.
你总结了所有这些信息。
So it's, like, you're re-expressing yourself in certain terms
所以，就像你在某些方面重新表达自己一样
of a weighted combination of your entire neighborhood.
整个社区的加权组合。
That's what attention does,
这就是注意力，
and you can add feed-forward layers to basically sort of compute new features for you.
并且您可以添加前馈层，以便为您计算新功能。
Um, now, um so the first part is going to be about how, like,
嗯，现在，嗯，所以第一部分将是关于如何，如，
some of the properties of self attention actually help us in text generation, like,
自我关注的一些属性实际上帮助我们生成文本，比如
what inductive biases are actually useful,
什么归纳偏差实际上有用，
and we empirically showed that indeed they,
我们凭经验表明他们确实
they move the needle in text generation.
他们在文本生成中移动针。
And this is going to be about machine translation,
这将是关于机器翻译，
but there were other work also that we'll talk about later.
但还有其他工作我们稍后会讨论。
So [NOISE] now with this, uh,
所以[NOISE]现在用这个，呃，
with this sort of, uh,
有这种，呃，
with this attention mechanism you get this- we get a constant path length.
通过这种注意机制，你得到了这个 - 我们得到一个恒定的路径长度。
So all pairs or a word can in-
所以所有对或一个词都可以 -
position can interact with any position, every position simultaneously.
位置可以同时与任何位置，每个位置相互作用。
Um, hopefully if the number of positions is not too many.
嗯，希望如果职位数量不是太多。
Uh, attention just by virtue of, like,
呃，注意力就像，就像，
it's a construction, you have a softmax,
它是一种结构，你有一个softmax，
you have these gating and multiplicative interactions.
你有这些门控和乘法互动。
And again, I'm not gonna be able to explain why,
而且，我不能解释为什么，
but it's, it's interesting, like,
但是，它很有趣，就像，
you've seen these models, like,
你见过这些模特，比如
even, even the, uh,
甚至，甚至，呃，
even Pixel, PixelCNN, uh, or, um,
甚至Pixel，PixelCNN，呃，或者，嗯，
when it was actually modeling images,
当它实际建模图像时，
they explicitly had to add these multiplicative interactions inside the model to,
他们明确地必须在模型中添加这些乘法交互，
to basically beat RNNs,
基本上击败了RNN，
and attention just by construction gets this because you're,
建筑的关注得到了这个，因为你，
you're multiplying the attention probabilities with your, with your activations.
你的注意概率与你的激活相乘。
It's trivial to parallelize, why?
并行化很简单，为什么？
Because you can just do attention with matmuls, especially the variant that we use in our paper,
因为你可以用matmuls来关注，特别是我们在论文中使用的变体，
uh, in our work.
呃，在我们的工作中。
And, uh, so now the question is
而且，呃，现在的问题是
convolutional sequence to- convolutional sequence models have been very successful in,
卷积序列到卷积序列模型已经非常成功，
in, in, in ge- generative tasks for text.
在文本的生成任务中。
Can we actually do the same or achieved the same with, uh,
我们可以实际做同样的事情或者实现同样的目标，呃，
with, uh, attention as our primary workhorse for representation learning.
呃，注意力是我们代表学习的主要工具。
Um, so just to sort of add some context and there's been some,
嗯，所以只是为了添加一些上下文而且有一些，
there's been some- up to- up to the transformer there have been a lot of
有一些变压器已经有很多了
great work on using self attention primarily for classification within.
使用自我注意力的主要工作主要是用于分类。
There was, there was work on self attention within the confines of,
有，在范围内有自我关注的工作，
like, recurrent neural networks.
比如，递归神经网络。
Um, perhaps the closest to us is the,
嗯，也许离我们最近的是，
is the memory networks,
是内存网络，
uh, by Weston, Sukhbaatar,
呃，由Weston，Sukhbaatar，
where they actually had a version of recurrent attention,
他们实际上有一个经常关注的版本，
but they didn't have, uh,
但他们没有，呃，
but they didn't actually- empirically,
但他们实际上没有 - 经验，
they didn't show it to work on sort of conditional modeling, like,
他们没有表明它可以用于某种条件建模，比如，
uh, translation and their mechanism was, uh, like,
呃，翻译和他们的机制是，呃，喜欢，
they were using sort of a fixed- they were using a fixed query at every step.
他们使用的是固定的 - 他们在每一步都使用固定的查询。
So there's- it, it leaves something to be desired.
所以，它有一些不足之处。
They still had this question, is it actually going to work, um, on,
他们还有这个问题，它真的会起作用吗，嗯，上，
on, on large scale machine translation systems or large-scale text generation systems.
在大型机器翻译系统或大型文本生成系统上。
So this is sort of the, the culmination of, um,
所以这就是嗯的高潮，嗯，
of the, the self attention, our self attention work.
自我关注，自我关注工作。
This is the tran- the- and we put it together in the transformer model.
这是转换 - 我们将它们放在变压器模型中。
And, uh, so how does this look like?
而且，呃，这看起来怎么样？
So we're going to use attention pri- we're going to use
所以我们将使用注意力 - 我们将要使用
attention primarily for computing representations so- of your input.
主要关注计算表示的输入。
Imagine you're doing English to German translation.
想象一下，你正在做英语到德语的翻译。
So you have your words, and notice that,
所以你有你的话，并注意到，
uh, attention is, uh, permutation invariant.
呃，注意力是，呃，排列不变。
So you just change the order of your positions.
所以你只需改变你的职位顺序。
You change the order of your words and, and,
你改变了你的单词的顺序，和，
uh, it's not going to affect the actual output.
呃，它不会影响实际输出。
So in ord- in order to maintain order we add,
所以在ord-为了维持我们添加的订单，
we add position representations.
我们添加位置表示。
And, uh, there's two kinds that we tried in the paper,
而且，呃，我们在论文中试过两种，
these, these fantastic sinusoids with no entropy invented.
这些，这些奇妙的正弦曲线没有发明熵。
And we also use learned representations which are
我们还使用了学到的表示
very plain vanilla both of them work equally well.
非常普通的香草，它们都同样有效。
Um, and, uh, so,
嗯，呃，所以，
so first we have- so the encoder looks as follows, right?
所以首先我们有 - 所以编码器看起来如下，对吗？
So we have a self attention layer that just recomputes the representation, uh,
所以我们有一个自我关注层，只是重新计算表示，呃，
for every position simultaneously using attention,
对于每个位置同时使用注意力，
then we have a feed-forward layer.
然后我们有一个前馈层。
And we also have residual,
我们也有残余，
residual connections and I'll,
残余连接，我会，
I'll sort of give you a glimpse of what these residual connections
我会给你一些这些残余连接的一瞥
might be bringing that is between every,
可能会带来每一个，
every layer, and the input we have a skip connection that just adds the activations.
每一层，输入我们有一个跳过连接，只是添加激活。
Uh, and then this tuple of, uh,
呃，然后这个元组，呃，
self attention and feed-forward layer just essentially repeats.
自我关注和前馈层基本上重复。
Now, on the decoder side, uh,
现在，在解码器方面，呃，
we've- we, we have a sort of standard encoder decoder architecture.
我们 - 我们有一种标准的编码器解码器架构。
On the decoder side, we mimic a language model using self attention,
在解码器方面，我们使用自我注意来模仿语言模型，
and the way to mimic a language model using self attention is to impose
并且使用自我注意来模仿语言模型的方式是强加
causality by just masking out the positions that you can look at.
通过掩盖你可以看到的位置的因果关系。
So basically, uh,
所以基本上，呃，
the first position it's- it can't look forward, it's illegal to look forward.
第一个位置 - 它不能向前看，向前看是违法的。
It can look at itself because we actually shift the input.
它可以看自己因为我们实际上改变了输入。
Um, so it's not copying, uh.
嗯，所以不是复制，呃。
It's kind of surprising that parti- with these models,
与这些模型分开是令人惊讶的，
it's very easy to copy at one point,
一次复制很容易，
when early on it was even harder to ge- you know,
什么时候开始就更难以了解你，
do copying with recurrent models.
使用循环模型进行复制。
But now, at least, you can copy really well,
但现在，至少，你可以复制得很好，
which is a positive sign, I think overall.
这是一个积极的迹象，我认为总的来说。
Um, but, uh, so now on the decoder side, uh,
嗯，但是，呃，现在在解码器方面，呃，
we have, uh, we have
我们有，呃，我们有
this causal self attention layer followed by encoder-decoder attention,
这个因果自我关注层接着是编码器 - 解码器关注，
where we actually attend to the, uh,
我们实际上在哪里，呃，
last layer of the encoder and a feed-forward layer, and this tripled,
编码器的最后一层和一个前馈层，这个三倍，
repeats a mul- a few times,
重复多次，
and at the end we have the standard cross-entropy loss.
最后我们有标准的交叉熵损失。
Um, and, um, so, um, sort of,
嗯，嗯，所以，嗯，有点像，
staring at the- at,
盯着这里，
at our parti- at the particular variant of the self-
在我们自己的特定变体的自我
of the attention mechanis- mechanism that we use,
我们使用的注意力机制，
we went for both- we went for simplicity and speed.
我们去了两个 - 我们去了简单和速度。
So, um, so how do you actually compute attention?
那么，嗯，你怎么实际计算注意力呢？
So imagine you want to re-represent the position e2.
所以想象你想重新代表e2的位置。
And, uh, we're going to first linearly,
而且，呃，我们首先是线性的，
linearly transform it into, uh, a query,
将其线性转换为呃查询，
and then we're gonna linearly transform
然后我们将线性转换
every position in your neighborhood
您附近的每个位置
or let's say every position at the input because this is the,
或者让我们说输入的每个位置，因为这是，
uh, uh, the encoder side,
呃，编码器方面，
to, uh, a key.
呃，一把钥匙。
And these linear transformations can actually be thought as features,
这些线性变换实际上可以被认为是特征，
and I'll talk more about it later on.
我稍后会谈到它。
So it's like- it's, it's basically a bilinear form.
所以它就像 - 它，它基本上是双线性形式。
You're projecting these vectors into a space where dot product is
您将这些向量投影到点积的空间中
a good- where just a dot product is a good proxy for similarity.
好的 - 只是一个点积是相似性的良好代理。
Okay? So now, you have your logit,
好的？那么现在，你有你的logit，
so you just do a so- softmax computer convex combination.
所以你只需要做一个这样的softmax计算机凸组合。
And now based on this convex combination,
现在基于这个凸组合，
you're going to then re-express e2 or in
你要重新表达e2或者
terms of this convex combination of all the vectors of all these positions.
所有这些位置的所有向量的这种凸组合的术语。
And before doing- before doing the convex combination,
在做之前 - 做凸组合之前，
we again do a linear transformation to produce values.
我们再次进行线性转换以产生价值。
And then we do a second linear transformation just to
然后我们进行第二次线性转换
mix this information and pass it through a- pass it through a feedforward layer.
混合这些信息并传递给它 - 通过前馈层。
And this is- um,
这就是，
and all of this can be expressed basically
所有这些都可以基本表达出来
in two- in two- in two-matrix multiplications,
在两个双矩阵乘法中，
and the square root factor is just to make sure that these,
平方根因子只是为了确保这些，
these dot products don't blow up.
这些点产品不会爆炸。
It's just a scaling factor.
这只是一个缩放因子。
And, uh, and, and,
而且，呃，和，和，
wha- why is this particular- why is
哇 - 为什么这个特别 - 为什么
this mechanism attractive? Well, it's just really fast.
这种机制吸引人？嗯，它真的很快。
You can do this very quickly on a GPU,
你可以在GPU上快速完成这项工作，
and simul- you can do it simultaneously for
和同时 - 你可以同时做到
all positions with just two matmuls and a softmax.
只有两个matmuls和一个softmax的所有位置。
Um, on the decoder side it's,
嗯，在解码器方面，
it's exactly the same,
它完全一样，
except we impose causality by just adding 10 e- minus 10 e9 to the logits.
除了我们通过在logits中添加10 e-minus 10 e9来强加因果关系。
So it basi- it's just- you just get zero probabilities on those positions.
所以它只是 - 你只是在这些位置上获得零概率。
So we just impose causality by, by adding these,
所以我们只是通过添加这些因素来强加因果关系，
uh, highly negative values on the attention- on the attention logits.
呃，关注注意力的注意力非常负面的价值观。
Um, is, is everything-
嗯，是，一切 -
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
I thought that was a question.
我认为这是一个问题。
So, um, [LAUGHTER] okay so attention is really, uh, attention is cheap.
所以，嗯，[笑声]好的，所以关注真的是，呃，注意力很便宜。
So because it's- because this variant of
所以因为它 - 因为这个变种
attention just involve two- involves two matrix multiplications,
注意只涉及两个 - 涉及两个矩阵乘法，
it's quadratic in the length of your sequence.
它是你序列长度的二次方。
And now what's the computational profile of RNNs or convolutions?
现在RNN或卷积的计算轮廓是什么？
They're quadratic in the dimension.
它们在维度上是二次的。
Because, basically, you can just think of a convolution just flattening
因为，基本上，你可以想到卷积只是扁平化
your input or just applying a linear transformation on top of it, right?
你的输入或只是在它上面应用线性变换，对吧？
So- and when does this actually become very attractive?
那么 - 这什么时候真的变得非常有吸引力？
This becomes very, very attractive when your dimension is,
当你的尺寸是，这变得非常非常有吸引力，
uh, much larger than your length.
呃，比你的长度大得多。
Which is the case for machine translation.
机器翻译的情况如何。
Now, we will talk about cases when there's- when the- when this is not true,
现在，我们将讨论有何情况 - 何时 - 何时不成立，
and we have to- we have to do a- we have to make other model developments.
我们必须 - 我们必须做 - 我们必须进行其他模型开发。
Um, but, uh, but for
嗯，但是，呃，但是
short sequences or sequences where
短序列或序列
your length does- where your dimension dominates length,
你的长度确实 - 你的尺寸在哪里占主导地位，
attention is a very- has a very favorable computation profile.
注意力是非常有利的计算特征。
And as you can see, it's about four times faster than an RNN.
正如您所看到的，它比RNN快四倍。
Um, um, and, and faster than
嗯，嗯，而且比
a convolutional model where the- you have a kernel of- like filter with, uh, three.
一个卷积模型，你有一个类似过滤器的内核，呃，三个。
So, so there's still one problem.
所以，还有一个问题。
Now, here's something- so in language,
现在，这里有一些东西 - 所以语言，
typically, we want to know, like,
通常，我们想知道，像，
who did what to whom, right?
谁做了什么对谁，对吧？
So now, imagine you applied a convolutional filter.
所以现在，想象一下你应用了一个卷积滤波器。
Because you actually have
因为你真的有
different linear transformations based on let- relative distances,
基于let-relative距离的不同线性变换，
like this, this, this, this,
像这样，这个，这个，这个，
linear transformation on the word who, uh, o- o- on the concept,
关于这个词的线性变换，呃，o- o-关于概念，
we can have- can learn this concept of who and, and, and,
我们可以 - 可以学习谁和和的概念，和
pick out different information from this embedding of the word I.
从这个单词的嵌入中挑选出不同的信息。
And this linear transformation,
而这个线性变换，
the lre- the red linear transformation can pick out different information
lre-红色线性变换可以选出不同的信息
from kicked and the blue linear transformation can pick out different,
从踢和蓝色线性转换可以挑出不同的，
different information from ball.
来自球的不同信息。
Now, when you have a single attention layer, this is difficult.
现在，当你有一个关注层时，这很难。
Because all- because they're just a convex combination
因为所有 - 因为它们只是一个凸起的组合
where you have the same linear transformation everywhere.
你到处都有相同的线性变换。
All that's available to you is just a- is just mixing proportions.
所有可用的只是a-只是混合比例。
So you can't pick out different pieces of information from different places.
所以你不能从不同的地方挑选出不同的信息。
Well, what if we had one attention layer for who?
那么，如果我们有一个关注层为谁呢？
So you can think of an attention layer as something like a feature detector almost,
所以你可以把注意力层看作几乎像特征探测器的东西，
like, because a particular- it,
喜欢，因为特定的，
it might try to- it might- because it carries with it a linear transformation,
它可能会尝试 - 它可能 - 因为它带有线性变换，
so it's projecting them in a space that- which starts caring maybe about syntax,
所以它将它们投射到一个空间中 - 这开始关心语法，
or it's projecting in this space which starts caring about who or what.
或者它正在这个开始关心谁或什么的空间中投射。
Uh, then we can have another attention layer for or attention head for what,
呃，那么我们可以有另一个关注层或注意力为什么，
did what, and other- another attention head for,
做了什么，和其他 - 另一个注意力，
for, for whom- to whom.
为谁而为谁。
And all of this can actually be done in parallel,
所有这一切实际上可以并行完成，
and that's actually- and that's exactly what we do.
而这实际上 - 这正是我们所做的。
And for efficiency, instead of actually
为了效率，而不是实际
having these dimensions operating in a large space,
这些尺寸在大空间内运行，
we just- we just reduce the dimensionality of all these heads
我们只是 - 我们只是减少所有这些头的维度
and we operate these attention layers in parallel, sort of bridging the gap.
我们并行操作这些注意力层，弥补了差距。
Now, here's a, uh,
现在，这是一个，呃，
perhaps, well, here's a little quiz.
或许，好吧，这是一个小小的测验。
I mean, can you actually- is there
我的意思是，你真的可以吗？
a combination of heads or is there a configuration in which you can,
头部的组合或是否有可以配置的配置，
actually, exactly simulate a convolution probably with more parameters?
实际上，可能使用更多参数来精确模拟卷积？
I think there should be a simple way to show that if you
我想应该有一个简单的方法来表明，如果你
had mo- more heads or heads are a function of positions,
有更多的头或头是位置的函数，
you could probably just simulate a convolution,
你可能只是模拟一个卷积，
but- although with a lot of parameters.
但是 - 尽管有很多参数。
Uh, so it can- in, in,
呃，所以它可以进去，
in the limit, it can actually simulate a convolution.
在极限中，它实际上可以模拟卷积。
Uh, and it also- we can al- we can continue to enjoy the benefits of parallelism,
呃，它也 - 我们可以继续享受并行的好处，
but we did increase the number of softmaxes
但我们确实增加了softmax的数量
because each head then carries with it a softmax.
因为每个头随身携带一个softmax。
But the amount of FLOPS didn't change because we-
但FLOPS的数量没有改变，因为我们 -
instead of actually having these heads operating in very large dimensions,
而不是实际上这些头在非常大的尺寸上操作，
they're operating in very small dimensions.
它们的运行范围非常小。
Um, so, uh, when we applied this on, on,
嗯，呃，当我们把它应用于，
on machine translation, um,
机器翻译，嗯，
we were able to drama- uh, dramatically outperform,
我们能够戏剧性地表现出色，表现出色，
uh, previous results on English-German and English-French translation.
呃，以前的英语 - 德语和英语 - 法语翻译结果。
So we had a pretty standard setup: 32,000-word vocabularies,
所以我们有一个非常标准的设置：32,000个单词的词汇，
WordPiece encodings, WMT14-, uh,
WordPiece编码，WMT14-，呃，
WMT 2014, uh, was our test set,
WMT 2014，呃，是我们的测试集，
2013 did the dev set.
2013年开发了设定。
And, uh, and some of these results were much stronger than even our previous ensemble models.
而且，呃，这些结果中的一些甚至比我们之前的合奏模型强得多。
And, um, and on English-French also,
而且，嗯，还有英语 - 法语，
we had some- we had some very favorabl- favorable results.
我们有一些 - 我们有一些非常有利的结果。
Uh, and we- and we are,
呃，我们 - 我们是，
we, we, we achieved state of the art.
我们，我们，我们取得了最先进的技术。
Now, ste- stepping back a bit, uh,
现在，退一步，呃，
I- I'm not claiming that we,
我 - 我没有声称我们，
we arrived at an architecture that has better expressivity than an LSTM.
我们得到的结构比LSTM具有更好的表现力。
I mean, there's, there's, there's,
我的意思是，有，有，有，
there's theorems that are- that say that LSTMs can model any function.
有定理 - 说LSTM可以模拟任何函数。
Um, perhaps, all we did was just build an architecture that was good for SGD.
嗯，或许，我们所做的只是建立一个对SGD有利的架构。
Because stochastic gradient descent could just train this architecture really well,
因为随机梯度下降可以很好地训练这个架构，
because the gradient dynamics and attention are very simple attentions,
因为梯度动力学和注意力都非常简单，
just a linear combination.
只是一个线性组合。
And, uh, um, I think that's- I,
而且，恩，嗯，我想 - 我，
I think that's actually favorable.
我认为这实际上是有利的。
But hopefully, uh, as we- as we go on,
但希望，呃，就像我们一样，我们继续
but the- well, I'd,
但是，好吧，我，
I'd also like to point out that, you know,
我还要指出，你知道，
we do explicit mo- we do explicitly model all,
我们做明确的莫 - 我们明确地模仿所有，
all path connection, all, all,
所有路径连接，全部，全部，
all pairwise connections and it has its adva- advantage of a very clear modeling,
所有成对连接，它具有非常清晰的建模的优势，
very clear relationships directly between, between any two words.
任何两个词之间直接关系非常明确。
Um, and, like, hopefully we'll be able to also
嗯，希望我们也能够
show that there are other inductive biases.
表明还有其他归纳偏见。
That it's not just like building more architectures that,
这不仅仅是建立更多的架构，
that are good for- that are good inductive biases for SGD.
这对SGD来说是好的诱导偏见。
So frameworks, a lot of our work was initially pushed out in tensor2tensor.
所以框架，我们的很多工作最初是在tensor2tensor中推出的。
Maybe that might change in the future with the arrival of JAX.
随着JAX的到来，未来可能会发生变化。
There's ano- there's a framework also from Amazon called Sockeye.
还有一个来自亚马逊的框架称为Sockeye。
There's also Fairseq, uh, the se- the
还有Fairseq，呃，这个
convolutional sequence-to-sequence toolkit from Facebook that the,
来自Facebook的卷积序列到序列工具包，
they prob- I'm actually not sure if it has a transformer implementation,
他们有问题 - 我实际上不确定它是否有变压器实现，
but they have some really good sequence-to-sequence models as well.
但它们也有一些非常好的序列到序列模型。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
So the importance of residuals.
所以残差的重要性。
So, uh, we have these resil- residual connections, uh, between, um,
那么，呃，我们有这些弹性残差连接，呃，介于...之间，嗯，
so we have these residual connections that go from here to- here to here,
所以我们有这些剩余的连接，从这里到这里，
here to here, like between every pair of layers, and it's interesting.
在这里，就像在每对图层之间，这很有趣。
So we, um, we- so what we do is we just
所以我们，嗯，我们 - 我们所做的就是我们
add the position informations at the input to the model.
在模型的输入处添加位置信息。
And, uh, we don't infuse- we don't infuse
而且，呃，我们没有注入 - 我们没有注入
or we don't inject position information at every layer.
或者我们不会在每一层注入位置信息。
So when, uh, we severed these residual connections and we loo- stared at these,
所以当呃，我们切断了这些剩余的连接，我们就这样关注，
uh, stared at these attention distributions, this is the center or,
呃，盯着这些注意力分布，这是中心或者，
sort of, the middle map is this attention distribution.
中间地图就是这种注意力分布。
You actually- basically, it- it's been unable to pick this diagonal.
你实际上 - 基本上，它 - 它无法选择这个对角线。
It should have a very strong diagonal focus.
它应该具有非常强的对角焦点。
And so what has happened was these residuals
所以发生的事情就是这些残差
were carrying this position information to every layer.
把这个位置信息带到每一层。
And because these subsequent layers had no notion of position,
而且因为这些后续层没有位置概念，
they were fi- finding it hard to actually attend.
他们发现很难真正参加。
This is the encoder-decoder attention which typically ends up being diagonal.
这是编码器 - 解码器的注意力，通常最终是对角线。
Now, so then we, uh, we said okay.
现在，那么我们，呃，我们说好了。
So then we actually continued with- continued to sever the residuals,
那么我们实际上继续 - 继续切断残差，
but we added position information back in at every layer.
但我们在每一层都添加了位置信息。
We injected position information back in.
我们重新注入了位置信息。
And we didn't recover the accuracy,
我们没有恢复准确性，
but we did get some of this,
但我们确实得到了一些，
sort of, diagonal focus back in.
一种对角线焦点。
So the residuals are doing more, but they're certainly,
所以残差做得更多，但他们肯定是，
definitely moving this position information to the model there.
肯定将这个位置信息移动到那里的模型。
They're pumping this position information through the model.
他们通过模型抽取这个位置信息。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
So, so that was- that was- so, so now we saw that,
那么，那就是 - 那么，所以现在我们看到了，
you know, being able to, sort of,
你知道，能够，有点，
model both long- and short-,
长短模型，
short-term relationships, uh, sh- uh, long and,
短暂的关系，呃，长，和，
long- and short-distance relationships with,
长距离和短距离的关系，
with attention is beneficial for, for text generation.
注意对于文本生成是有益的。
Um, what kind of inductive,
嗯，什么样的归纳，
inductive biases lay- actually, uh, appear, or what,
归纳偏见 - 实际上，呃，出现或是什么，
what kind of phenomena appear in images and something that we constantly see- constantly
什么样的现象出现在图像和我们经常看到的东西 - 不断
see in images and music is this notion of
看到图像和音乐是这个概念
repeating structure that's very similar to each other?
重复彼此非常相似的结构？
You have these motifs that repeat in, in different scales.
你有不同尺度的重复这些图案。
So, for example, there's a b- it's another artificial but beautiful example of
所以，例如，有一个b-它是另一个人为但美丽的例子
self-similarity where you have this Van Gogh painting where this texture or these,
自我相似，你有这个梵高画这里的纹理或这些，
these little objects just repeat.
这些小物件只是重复一遍。
These images are- these different pieces of the image are very sa- similar to each other,
这些图像是 - 这些不同的图像彼此非常相似，
but they might have different scales.
但他们可能有不同的规模。
Uh, again in music,
呃，又是音乐，
here's a motif that repeats, uh,
这是一个重复的主题，呃，
that could have- it could have, like,
可能有 - 可能有，像，
di- various, like, spans of time between in, in, between it.
各种各样的，例如，在它之间，之间，之间的时间跨度。
So, um, so, so this,
所以，嗯，所以，这个，
so we, we, we,
所以我们，我们，我们，
we attempted after this to see, well,
我们试图在此之后看到，好吧，
to ask this question: can self-attention help us in modeling other objects like images?
问这个问题：自我关注可以帮助我们建模像图像这样的其他对象吗？
So the, the path we took was, sort of,
那么，我们采取的路径是，
standard auto-regressive image modeling the- or probabilistic image modeling, not GANs.
标准自回归图像建模概率或概率图像建模，而不是GAN。
Because it was- well, one, it was very easy.
因为它很好，一个，很容易。
We had a language model almost.
我们几乎有一个语言模型。
So this is just like language modeling on images.
所以这就像图像上的语言建模一样。
Uh, and also training at maximum,
呃，还有最大的训练，
likely, it allows you to, sort of,
可能，它允许你，有点，
measure, measure how well you're doing on,
衡量，衡量你做得多好，
uh, on, on your held-out set.
呃，在你举行的集合上。
Uh, and it also gives you diversity,
呃，它也给你多样性，
so you hopefully are covering all possible, uh,
所以你希望覆盖所有可能的，呃，
different kinds of images you- So, um,
各种各样的图像 - 所以，嗯，
and to this point there's al- we had
到目前为止，我们已经拥有了
an advantage that's also been- there are- there've been
这种优势也一直存在
good work on using recurrent models like PixelRNN and PixelCNN,
使用像PixelRNN和PixelCNN这样的周期性模型的好工作，
that, that we're actually getting some very good compression rates. Um-
那，我们实际上得到了一些非常好的压缩率。 UM-
And, um, again here,
而且，嗯，再来一次，
originally the argument was that, well, you know,
最初的论点是，嗯，你知道，
in images because there- because you want symmetry,
在图像中因为你想要对称，
because you want like if you have a face,
因为如果你有脸，你想要
you want, you want one ear to sort of match with the other.
你想要的，你想要一只耳朵与另一只耳朵匹配。
If you had a large receptive field,
如果你有一个大的感受野，
which you could potentially get with attention at a lower computational cost,
您可以以较低的计算成本获得关注，
then it should benefit- then it should be quite beneficial for, for images,
然后它应该受益 - 那么对于图像，它应该是非常有益的
for images and you wouldn't need many layers like you do in
对于图像而言，你不需要像你那样需要很多层
convolutions to actually get dependencies between these far away pixels.
卷积实际上获得这些遥远像素之间的依赖关系。
So it seem like self-attention would have been a- what, what,
所以看起来自我关注会是什么，什么，
what was already a good computational mechanism, right?
什么是一个很好的计算机制，对吧？
But this sort of- but it was actually interesting to see
但是这种 - 但实际上很有趣
how it even modeled- naturally modeled self-similarity,
它是如何建模的 - 自然地建模自相似性，
and people have used self-similarity in image generation like, you know, uh,
人们在图像生成中使用了自相似性，就像你知道的那样，呃，
there's this really cool work by Efros where they actually see, okay,
Efros真的很酷，他们实际上看到了，好吧，
in the training set, what are those patches that are really,
在训练集中，那些真正的补丁是什么，
that are really similar to me?
那真的和我相似吗？
And based on the patches that are really similar to me,
基于与我非常相似的补丁，
I'm going to fill up the information.
我要填写这些信息。
So it's like actually doing image generation.
所以它就像实际上做图像生成一样。
Uh, there is this really classic work called
呃，有这个非常经典的作品叫做
non-local means where they do image denoising,
非本地意味着它们进行图像去噪，
where they want to denoise this sort of,
他们想要在哪里去噪，
this patch P. And they say,
这个补丁P.他们说，
I'm going to- based on my similarity between all other patches in my image,
我将基于我的图像中所有其他补丁之间的相似性，
I'm going to compute some function of content-based similarity,
我要计算基于内容的相似性的一些功能，
and based on the similarity I'm going to pull information.
并根据相似性我将提取信息。
So as- and exploiting this fact that images are very self-similar.
因此，并利用这一事实，即图像非常相似。
And, uh, uh, this has also been sort of,
而且，呃，这也是一种，
uh, applied in some recent work.
呃，适用于最近的一些工作。
Now if you just took this encoder self-attention mechanism
现在，如果你只是采取这种编码器自我关注机制
and just replace these word embeddings with patches,
并用补丁替换这些单词嵌入，
and that's kind of exactly what it's doing.
这就是它正在做的事情。
It's, it's computing this notion of content-based similarity
它是，它正在计算这种基于内容的相似性的概念
between these elements and then based on this content-based similarity,
在这些元素之间，然后基于这种基于内容的相似性，
it constructs a convex combination that essentially brings these things together.
它构造了一个凸起的组合，基本上将这些东西结合在一起。
So it's, it's a very ni- it was,
所以，它是一个非常非常的，
it was quite- it was very pleasant to see that,
这真是太令人愉快了，
oh, this is a differentiable way of doing non-local means.
哦，这是一种做到非本地手段的可区分方式。
And, uh, and we took the transformer architecture and replaced words with pixels.
而且，呃，我们采用变压器架构并用像素替换了单词。
Uh, there was some- there were some architecture adjustments to do.
呃，有一些 - 有一些架构调整要做。
And, uh, so this was but- this was
而且，呃，所以这是 - 但是 - 这是
basically the kind of- it was very similar to the original work,
基本上那种 - 它与原作非常相似，
and here the position representations instead of being, you know,
这里是位置表示，而不是，你知道，
one-dimensional, they were- because we are not dealing with sequences,
一维，他们是 - 因为我们没有处理序列，
we have two-dimensional position representations.
我们有二维位置表示。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
So I pointed out before,
所以我之前指出过，
attention is a very com- very favorable computational profile
注意力是非常有利的计算特征
if your length- if your dimension dominates length,
如果你的长度 - 如果你的尺寸占主导地位，
which if- which is absolutely untrue for,
如果 - 这绝对是不真实的，
absolutely untrue for images.
绝对不真实的图像。
Uh, because even for like 32 by- even for 32 by 32 images,
呃，因为即使是32比32的图像，
when you flatten them and you- and you flatten them, you have 30- you get 30,
当你把它们弄平而你 - 然后你把它们弄平，你有30-你得到30，
72 positions, uh, so it's your standard CFIR image.
72个位置，呃，所以这是你的标准CFIR图像。
Um, so simple solution, uh,
嗯，这么简单的解决方案，呃，
because like convolutions of- I mean,
因为喜欢卷积 - 我的意思是，
you get- convolutions are basically looked
你得到了 - 基本上看了卷积
at local windows and you get translational equivariance.
在本地窗口，你得到转换等价。
We said, "Okay. Let's adopt the same strategy."
我们说：“好的。让我们采用相同的策略。”
And also there's a lot of spatial locality and images.
而且还有很多空间局部性和图像。
Uh, but now, we will still have a better computational profile.
呃，但现在，我们仍然会有更好的计算资料。
If your- if your receptive field is still smaller than your dimension,
如果您 - 如果您的感受野仍然小于您的尺寸，
you can afford- you can actually still do
你买得起 - 你实际上还可以做到
much more long distance computation than a standard convolution because you're,
比标准卷积更远的长距离计算，因为你，
uh, because you're quadratic in length.
呃，因为你的长度是二次方的。
So as long as we didn't increase our length beyond the dimension,
所以只要我们不增加超出尺寸的长度，
we still had a favorable computational profile.
我们仍然有一个有利的计算资料。
And so the way we did it was, uh,
所以我们这样做的方式是，呃，
we essentially had, uh,
我们基本上有，呃，
two kinds of rasterizations.
两种光栅化。
So we had a one-dimensional rasterization where you had a sort of single query block,
所以我们有一个单维光栅化，你有一个单一的查询块，
uh, which was, uh,
呃，这是，呃，
which was then attending or to the- into a larger memory block,
然后参加或进入更大的内存块，
uh, in this rasterized fashion along the- along, along the rows.
呃，沿着这条光栅化的方式沿着行。
Um, then we tried another form of rasterization,
嗯，然后我们尝试了另一种形式的光栅化，
falling standard two-dimensional locality,
下降的标准二维位置，
where you had- where we actually produced the image in,
你在哪里 - 我们实际生产图像的地方，
uh, in blocks and within each block we had a rasterization scheme.
呃，在块中和每个块内我们有一个光栅化方案。
Um, again, these- the image transformer layer was very similar.
嗯，再次，这些 - 图像变换器层非常相似。
We had two-dimensional position representations along
我们有二维位置表示
with query- with the same- with a very similar attention mechanism.
与查询相同 - 具有非常相似的注意机制。
Um, and we tried
嗯，我们试过了
both super-resolution and unconditional and conditional image generation.
超分辨率和无条件和条件图像生成。
Uh, this is- this is Ne- Niki Parmar,
呃，这是 - 这是Ne-Niki Parmar，
I and a co- and a few other authors from Brain,
我和其他一些来自Brain的作者，
um, and we presented it at ICML.
嗯，我们在ICML展示了它。
And, uh, we were able to achieve better perplexity than existing models.
而且，呃，我们能够比现有的模型更加困惑。
So PixelSNAIL is actually another model that used- mixed
所以PixelSNAIL实际上是另一种混合使用的模型
both convolutions and self-attention and they- they outperformed us on,
无论是革命和自我关注还是他们 - 他们都胜过我们，
on, on, on, on, bits per dimension.
on，on，on，on，bits per dimension。
So we were measuring perplexity because these are
所以我们正在测量困惑，因为这些是
probabilistic- these are probabilistic models.
概率 - 这些是概率模型。
It's like basically a language model of images and,
这就像基本上是图像的语言模型，
and it just- and your- and the factorization
它只是 - 和你 - 以及因子分解
of your language model just depends on how you rasterize.
你的语言模型只取决于你如何栅格化。
In the- in this- in the one-D rasterization,
在这里 - 在一维光栅化中，
we went first rows and then columns.
我们先行，然后是列。
In the two-D rasterization,
在二维光栅化中，
we went blockwise and inside each block we rasterized.
我们走向块状，在每个块内部进行栅格化。
On ImageNet, we achieved better perplexities, and,
在ImageNet上，我们实现了更好的困惑，并且，
uh, so yeah, I mean we're at a GAN level, right?
呃，是的，我的意思是我们处于GAN水平，对吧？
I mean this weird- this is- I think probabilist auto-regressive Image generation,
我的意思是这很奇怪 - 这是 - 我认为概率论自动回归图像生成，
uh, by this point had not reached GANs.
呃，到目前为止还没有达到GAN。
At ICLR 2019, there's a paper by Nal that actually uses self-attention and gets very,
在ICLR 2019年，纳尔的一篇论文实际上使用了自我关注并得到了非常的，
very good quality images.
质量非常好的图像。
But what we, what we observed was,
但我们所观察到的是，
we were getting structured objects fairly well.
我们得到的结构化对象相当不错。
Like can people recognize what the second row is?
人们可以认识到第二排是什么吗？
Cars. [OVERLAPPING]
汽车。 [重叠]
I heard- I said- most- almost everyone said cars.
我听说 - 我说 - 大多数 - 几乎每个人都说汽车。
I'm not going to ask who said something else, but yes, they're cars.
我不打算问谁说了什么，但是，是的，他们是汽车。
yeah. And, uh, so the- and the last row is another vehicles like,
是的。而且，呃，所以 - 和最后一排是另一种车辆，如，
uh, so essentially when structured jo- structured objects were easy to capture.
呃，基本上当结构化的jo-structured对象很容易被捕获时。
Um, like frogs and sort of,
嗯，像青蛙一样，
you know, objects that were camouflaged just turned into this mush.
你知道，被伪装的物体变成了这种糊状物。
Um, and- but on super resolution,
嗯，而且 - 但是超级分辨率，
now super-resolution is interesting because
现在超级分辨率很有意思，因为
there's a lot of conditioning information, right?
有很多条件信息，对吧？
And, uh, when you have a lot of conditioning information, the,
而且，呃，当你有很多调理信息时，
the sort of possible- you break- you,
那种可能 - 你打破了你，
you actually lock quite a few of the modes.
你实际上锁定了很多模式。
So there's only a few options you can have at the output.
因此，输出中只有几个选项。
And super- our super resolution results are much better.
超级 - 我们的超分辨率结果要好得多。
We were able to get better facial orientation and structure than previous work.
我们能够比以前的工作获得更好的面部定位和结构。
And these are samples at different temperatures and, uh, and, uh,
这些是不同温度下的样品，呃，呃，
and we wou- when we quantify this with actual human evaluators,
当我们用实际的人类评估者量化这个时，我们
we- like we flash an image and said,
我们 - 就像我们闪现一个图像说，
is this real, is this false?
这是真的吗，这是假的吗？
And we were able to, uh,
我们能够，呃，
we were able to fool humans like four
我们能像四个人一样愚弄人类
times better than previous results in super resolution.
比以前的超分辨率结果更好。
Again, these are not- these results like I, I guess the,
再次，这些不是 - 这些结果像我，我想，
the latest GAN result from Nvidia makes us look like a joke.
来自Nvidia的最新GAN结果让我们看起来像个笑话。
But, I mean this is,
但是，我的意思是，
I mean, we're starting later than GAN.
我的意思是，我们的起步晚于GAN。
So hopefully we'll catch up.
所以希望我们能赶上来。
But, but the point here is that this is an interesting inductive bias for images,
但是，这里的重点是，这是图像的一个有趣的归纳偏见，
so very natural inductive bias for images.
对图像非常自然的归纳偏差。
Um, and, uh, and,
嗯，呃，和，
and there is hope to apply it- for applying in classification and other such tasks also.
并且有希望将其应用于分类和其他此类任务。
Um, so one interesting thing,
嗯，这是一件有趣的事，
just to sort of both out of curiosity and
只是出于好奇和好奇
asking how good is maximum or like does maximum likelihood.
询问最大可能性有多好或最大可能性。
Well, one, does the model actually capture some interesting structure in the role?
嗯，其中一个，模型实际上是否捕获了角色中的一些有趣结构？
Second, do you get diversity?
第二，你有多样性吗？
Well, maximum likelihood should get diversity,
那么，最大可能性应该是多样性，
by, by virtue, by virtue of what it does.
通过，凭借它所做的一切。
Uh, so then we just- we did image completion.
呃，那么我们只是 - 我们做了图像完成。
And why is- why image completion because as soon as you
为什么 - 为什么图像完成，因为只要你
lock down half the image to the goal truth,
将图像的一半锁定到目标真相，
you're actually shaving off a lot of the possible modes.
你实际上正在削减很多可能的模式。
So you have a much easier time sampling.
因此，您可以更轻松地抽样。
So, uh, so the first is,
所以，呃，首先是，
uh, first is what we supply to the model.
呃，首先是我们为模型提供的东西。
The, the, the right row- the right most column is,
右边的行 - 最右边的列是，
is gold, and we were able to generate different samples.
是黄金，我们能够生成不同的样本。
But what was really interesting is the third row.
但真正有趣的是第三排。
Uh, so the rightmost column is- the rightmost column is gold.
呃，所以最右边的列是 - 最右边的列是金。
Uh, now if you look at the third row, this horse.
呃，现在如果你看第三排，这匹马。
So actually there's this sort of glimpse or a suggestion of a pull,
所以实际上有这种瞥见或建议拉，
but the model hallucinated a human in some of these,
但这些模特在其中一些人中产生了幻觉，
in some of these images,
在其中一些图像中，
which is interesting like in- it does capture at least
这很有意思，因为它至少可以捕获它
the data teaches it to capture some structure about the world.
数据教会它捕捉一些关于世界的结构。
Um, the dog is just cute and I guess it also shows that, you know,
嗯，狗很可爱，我猜它也表明，你知道，
there was this entire object,
有这整个对象，
this chair, that the model just completely refused to imagine.
这把椅子，模型完全拒绝想象。
So there's a lot of difficulty.
所以有很多困难。
And I guess Anna is gonna talk about
而且我想安娜会谈论
[NOISE] the another way to exploit self- self-similarity.
[NOISE]利用自我相似性的另一种方式。
Thank you.
谢谢。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
So thank you Ashish for the introduction.
谢谢Ashish的介绍。
Uh, so there's a lot of self-similarity in images.
呃，所以图像中有很多自相似之处。
There's also a lot of self-similarity in, in music.
在音乐方面也有很多自相似之处。
So we can imagine, transformer being a, a good model for it.
所以我们可以想象，变压器是一个很好的模型。
Uh, we- we're going to show how,
呃，我们 - 我们将展示如何，
uh, we can add more to,
呃，我们可以添加更多，
to the self attention, to think more about kind of
要自我关注，要多考虑一下
relational information and how that could help, uh, music generation.
关系信息以及它如何帮助，呃，音乐的产生。
[NOISE] So, uh, first I want to
[NOISE]所以，呃，首先我想
clarify what is the raw representation that we're working with right now.
澄清我们现在正在使用的原始表示形式。
So analogous to language,
所以类似于语言，
you can think about there's text and somebody is reading out a text,
你可以考虑有文字，有人正在读出文字，
so they add their kind of own intonations to it,
所以他们为它添加了自己的语调，
and then you have sound waves coming out of that speech.
然后你就会发出声音。
So for music there's a va- very similar kind of, uh,
所以对于音乐来说，有一种非常类似的，呃，
line of a generation where you say the composer has an idea,
你说作曲家有想法的一代人的路线，
uh, writes down the score and then,
呃，写下分数，然后，
a performer performs it and then you get sound.
表演者执行它然后你得到声音。
So what we're going to focus on today is mostly, uh,
那么我们今天要关注的主要是，呃，
you can think of the score but it's actually,
你可以想到得分，但事实上，
er, a performance, um,
呃，表演，嗯，
in that it's a symbolic representation where MIDI pianos were used and,
因为它是使用MIDI钢琴的符号表示，
uh, um, professional amateur, uh,
呃，呃，专业的业余爱好者，呃，
musicians were performing on the pianos.
音乐家们正在钢琴上表演。
So we have the recorded,
所以我们有记录，
uh, information of their playing.
呃，他们演奏的信息。
So in particular, um,
特别是，嗯，
at each time se- step modeling music as this sequential, uh,
每次将音乐建模为顺序，呃，
process, what is being output are, okay,
过程，输出的是什么，好吧，
turn this note on, ah,
转过这张便条啊，
advance the clock by this much,
这么多推进时钟，
and then turn this note off.
然后关闭此笔记。
And also there is, uh, dynamics information,
还有，呃，动态信息，
so when you turn the note on, you first say like,
所以当你打开音符时，首先要说的是，
how loud it's going to be.
会有多大声。
Uh, so traditionally, uh, modeling, uh,
呃，传统上，呃，造型，呃，
music as kind of a language,
音乐作为一种语言，
we've been using, uh, recurrent neural networks.
我们一直在使用，呃，递归神经网络。
And, um, because as Ashish introduced and, and talked about,
而且，嗯，因为正如Ashish介绍的那样，并且谈到了，
there is a lot of compression that needs to happen,
需要进行大量压缩，
like a long sequence has to be embedded into like a fixed length vector.
像长序列一样必须嵌入到固定长度的矢量中。
And that becomes hard when, uh,
当，呃，这变得很难
in music you have- you have repetition coming,
在你的音乐中 - 你有重复的到来，
um, at a distance.
嗯，远处。
So, uh, I'm first going to show you,
所以，呃，我首先要告诉你，
um, samples from, from the RNNs,
嗯，来自RNN的样本，
from a transformer and then from a music transformer that has
从一个变压器，然后从一个音乐变压器
the relative attention and kind of let you hear
让你听到的相对关注和善意
the differences and then I'll go into how we,
差异然后我会进入我们的方式，
uh, what are, what are the, uh,
呃，什么，有什么，呃，
modifications we needed to do on top of the, uh, transformer model.
我们需要在变压器模型上进行修改。
Uh, so here, uh,
呃，所以在这里，呃，
this task is kind of the image completion task.
此任务是一种图像完成任务。
So we give it an initial motif and then we ask the model to do continuations.
所以我们给它一个初始主题，然后我们要求模型做延续。
So this is the motif that we fed.
所以这就是我们喂养的主题。
[MUSIC] How many people recognize that?
[音乐]有多少人认识到了这一点？
Awesome. Okay. [LAUGHTER] Yeah,
真棒。好的。 [大笑]是的，
so this is a, uh,
所以这是一个，呃，
kind of a fragment from a Chopin Etude piece.
肖邦练习曲片中的片段。
And we're going to ask, uh,
我们要问，呃，
the RNN to do a continuation.
RNN继续做下去。
[NOISE]
[噪声]
[MUSIC]
[音乐]
So in here, like in the beginning, it was trying to repeat it.
所以在这里，就像在开始时一样，它试图重复它。
But very fast, it, er,
但是，非常快，呃，
wandered off into, its other different ideas.
徘徊，其他不同的想法。
So that's one challenge because it's, uh,
所以这是一个挑战，因为它是，呃，
not able to directly look back to what happened in the past, uh, and,
不能直接回顾过去发生的事情，呃，和
and can just look at kind of a blu- blurry version,
并且可以看一下蓝色模糊的版本，
and that blurry version becomes more and more blurry.
而模糊的版本变得越来越模糊。
Uh, so this is what the transformer does.
呃，这就是变压器所做的。
Uh, so so, uh, a detail is, uh,
呃，是这样，呃，细节是，呃，
these models are trained on half the length that you're hearing.
这些模型的训练长度是你听到的一半。
So we're kinda asking the model to generalize beyond the length that it's trained on.
因此，我们有点要求模型概括超出它训练的长度。
And you can see for this transformer,
你可以看到这个变压器，
it, it deteriorates beyond that.
它，它已经恶化了。
But it can hold the motif pretty consistent.
但它可以保持这个主题非常一致。
[MUSIC] Okay. You, you,
[音乐]好的。你，你，
you ge- you get the idea.
你知道了 - 你明白了。
[LAUGHTER] So initially, it was able to do this repetition really well.
[笑声]所以最初，它能够很好地完成这个重复。
Uh, so it was able to copy it very well.
呃，所以能够很好地复制它。
But beyond the length that was trained on,
但超出训练的长度，
it kinda didn't know how to cope with, like longer contexts.
它有点不知道如何处理，像更长的背景。
And, uh, what you see,
而且，呃，你看到的，
uh, the, the last one is from the music transformer.
呃，最后一个来自音乐变换器。
I think so that kind of [NOISE] the relational information.
我认为那种[NOISE]关系信息。
And you can just see visually how it's very consistent and kinda
你可以直观地看到它是如何非常一致和有点
repeating these [NOISE] these larger, uh, arcs.
重复这些[噪音]这些更大的呃弧线。
[MUSIC]
[音乐]
Yeah. So that was, uh, music transformer.
是啊。那就是，呃，音乐变换器。
And so in music,
在音乐中，
the, the self similarity that we talked about, uh,
我们谈到的自相似性，呃，
so we see, uh,
所以我们看到了，呃，
the motif here, and so,
这里的主题，等等，
so there we primed the model with a motif,
所以我们用一个图案引导模型，
and this is actually a sample,
这实际上是一个样本，
unconditioned sample from the model.
来自模型的无条件样本。
So nothing, er, there was no priming that the, uh,
没什么，呃，没有启动，呃，
model kinda had to create its own motif and then,
模特有点必须创造自己的主题，然后，
uh, do, uh, continuations from there.
呃，做，呃，那里的延续。
And here, uh, if we kinda look at it and analyze it a bit, you see,
在这里，呃，如果我们看一下它并稍微分析一下，你看，
uh, a lot of repetition,
呃，很多重复，
uh, with gaps in between.
呃，两者之间存在差距。
And if you look at the self attention structure,
如果你看看自我关注结构，
we actually do see the model,
我们确实看到了模型，
uh, looking at the relevant parts.
呃，看看相关部分。
Even if, if it was not immediately, uh, preceding it.
即使，如果它不是立即，呃，在它之前。
So, so here, uh,
所以，在这里，呃，
what I colored shaded out is where the motif, um, occurs.
我涂上阴影的是主题，嗯，发生的地方。
Uh, and you can, uh, see the different colors,
呃，你可以，呃，看到不同的颜色，
there's a different attention heads and they're kinda focusing,
有一个不同的注意力头，他们有点专注，
uh, among those, uh, grayed out sections.
呃，其中，呃，灰色的部分。
[NOISE] So I'll play the sample and we also have
[NOISE]所以我会播放样本，我们也有
a visualization that kind of shows you as the music is pa- uh,
一种可视化，可以将您视为音乐，
is being played or what notes it was attending to as it was predicting that note.
正在播放或正在播放的音符，因为它正在预测该音符。
And, uh, this was generated from scratch.
而且，呃，这是从头开始生成的。
And, uh, so the self attention is, um,
而且，呃，所以自我关注是，嗯，
from, from kind of note to note level or event to event level.
从，从注意级别或事件到事件级别。
So it's, it's quite low level.
所以它是，它的水平相当低。
Uh, so when you look at it, it's,
呃，所以当你看着它时，它是
it's ki- a little bit overwhelming.
这有点压倒性的。
It has like multiple heads and,
它有多个头，
er, a lot of things moving.
呃，很多东西在动。
Uh, but there's kind of these structural moments
呃，但是有一些结构性的时刻
where you would kind of see more of this, uh,
在哪里你会看到更多这个，呃，
clean, uh, kind of,
干净，呃，有点，
uh, sections where it's attending to.
呃，它所关注的部分。
[MUSIC]
[音乐]
VOkay. So, um,
VOkay。那么，嗯，
how, how did we do that?
怎么样，我们是怎么做到的？
And so starting from kind of the the regular attention mechanism,
从一般的注意机制开始，
we know it's, uh, a weighted average of the past history.
我们知道，呃，过去历史的加权平均值。
Uh, and the nice thing is, uh,
呃，好的是，呃，
however far it is, we have direct access to it.
无论如何，我们可以直接访问它。
So if we know, uh,
如果我们知道，呃，
there are kind of motifs that occurred,
发生了一些图案，
uh, in in early on in the piece,
呃，早在片中，
we're still able to based on, uh,
我们仍然可以基于，呃，
the fact that things that are similar,
事情是相似的，
uh, to be able to retrieve those.
呃，能够找回那些。
Um, but, uh, it also becomes,
嗯，但是，呃，它也变成了，
all the past becomes kind of a bag of words,
所有的过去都成了一堆文字，
like there is no structure of which came,
就像没有结构，
uh, before or after.
呃，之前或之后。
So there's the positional sinusoids that Ashish talked about.
所以Ashish谈到的是位置正弦曲线。
That, uh, basically in this, uh,
那个，呃，基本上就是这个，呃，
indices indexes into a sinusoids that are moving at different speeds.
指数指向以不同速度移动的正弦曲线。
And so close-by positions would have, uh,
所以附近的职位会有，呃，
a very similar kind of, uh,
一种非常相似的，呃，
cross section into those multiple sinusoids.
横截面成多个正弦曲线。
Uh, in contrast for, er,
呃，相比之下，呃，
for convolutions, you kinda have this, uh,
对于卷积，你有点这个，呃，
fixed filter that's moving around that captures the relative distance.
移动的固定过滤器捕获相对距离。
Like 1B4, 2B4.
像1B4,2B4。
And these are kind of, uh,
这些都是，呃，
in some ways like a rigid structure that allows you to be, uh,
在某些方面，像一个刚性的结构，让你成为，呃，
a kind of, uh, bring in the,
一种，呃，带来的，
the distance information very explicitly.
距离信息非常明确。
Um, you can imagine relative attention, um,
嗯，你可以想象相对的关注，嗯，
with the multiple heads, uh, at play,
多头，呃，在玩耍，
uh, to be some combination of these.
呃，成为这些的组合。
So, uh, on one hand,
所以，呃，一方面，
you can access, uh,
你可以访问，呃，
the the history very directly.
历史非常直接。
On the other hand, you also know, er,
另一方面，你也知道，呃，
how you rel- relate to this history.
你如何与这段历史联系起来。
Uh, capturing for example,
呃，捕捉，例如，
like translational invariance and, er,
像翻译不变性，呃，
and we, uh, and for example,
而我们，呃，等等，
we think one of the reasons why in the beginning, uh,
我们认为一开始的原因之一，呃，
priming samples that you heard that the, uh,
启动样品你听说过，呃，
music transformer was able to generate
音乐变压器能够产生
beyond the length that it was trained on at a very coherent way,
超出它以非常连贯的方式训练的长度，
is that it's able to kind of rely on this translational invariance to to carry,
它是否能够依赖这种平移不变性来携带，
uh, the relational information forward.
呃，关系信息向前发展。
So, if we take a closer look at how how how the,
所以，如果我们仔细看看如何如何，
how this works is, uh,
这是如何工作的，呃，
the regular transformer you have,
你有常规变压器，
you compare all the queries and keys,
你比较所有的查询和密钥，
so you get kind of this, uh, square matrix.
所以你得到了这个，呃，方阵。
You can think of it as like a self similarity,
你可以把它想象成一种自相似性，
uh, matrix, so it's, uh, a square.
呃，矩阵，所以它是，呃，一个正方形。
Uh, what relative attention does is,
呃，相对注意力是什么，
to add an additional term that thinks, uh,
添加一个认为的额外术语，呃，
that thinks about whenever you're comparing two things,
每当你比较两件事时都会想到
how far are you apart?
你有多远？
And also based on the content, do I,
而且还根据内容，我，
do I care about things that are two steps away or
我是否关心两步之遥的事情
three steps away or I maybe care about things that are recurring,
三步走了或者我可能关心经常发生的事情，
at kind of a periodical distance.
在某种周期性的距离。
And, uh, with that information gathered,
而且，呃，收集到的信息，
that influences, uh, the the similarity between positions.
这影响，呃，位置之间的相似性。
And in particular, uh,
特别是，呃，
this extra term is based on, um, the distance.
这个额外的术语是基于，嗯，距离。
So you wanna, uh,
所以你想，呃，
gather the embeddings, uh,
收集嵌入物，呃，
that's irrelevant to the, uh,
这与呃无关，呃，
the query key distances,
查询关键距离，
uh, on the [NOISE] on the logits.
呃，在logits上的[NOISE]上。
So, in translation, this,
所以，在翻译中，这个，
uh, has shown, uh,
呃，已经表明，呃，
a lot of improvement in,
很多改进，
um, for example English to to German translation.
嗯，例如英语到德语翻译。
Uh, but in translation,
呃，但在翻译中，
the sequences are usually quite short.
序列通常很短。
It's only a sentence to sentence.
这只是判刑的句子。
Uh, a translation for example,
呃，翻译，例如，
maybe 50 words or 100 words.
也许50个单词或100个单词。
But the music, er, samples that you've heard are in the range of 2,000 time-steps.
但是，您听过的音乐呃样本的时间步长为2,000。
So it's like 2,000 tokens need to be able to fit in memory.
所以它就像2,000个令牌需要能够适应内存。
So this was a problem, uh,
所以这是一个问题，呃，
because the original formulation relied on building this 3D tensor that's,
因为原来的配方依赖于构建这个3D张量，
uh, that's very large in memory.
呃，记忆力非常大。
Um, and and why this is the case?
嗯，为什么会这样呢？
It's because for every pair,
这是因为对于每一对，
uh, you look up what the,
呃，你抬头看看，
what the re- so you can compute what the relative distance is,
什么，你可以计算相对距离是什么，
and then you look up an embedding that corresponds to that distance.
然后你查找一个与该距离相对应的嵌入。
So, um, for like this there's a length by length, like L by L, uh, matrix.
所以，嗯，因为这样的长度有长度，比如L by L，呃，矩阵。
You need like, uh,
你需要，呃，
to collect embeddings for each of the positions and that's, uh,
收集每个职位的嵌入，那是，呃，
depth D. So that gives us the 3D.
深度D.这样就给了我们3D。
What we realized is,
我们意识到的是，
you can actually just directly multiply the queries and the embedding distances.
实际上你可以直接乘以查询和嵌入距离。
[NOISE] And they, uh,
[NOISE]他们，呃，
come out kind of in a different order,
出来的有点不同，
because now you have the queries ordered by a relative distance,
因为现在你有相对距离排序的查询，
but you need the queries ordered by keys, uh,
但你需要按键排序的查询，呃，
which is kind of a absolute by absolute, uh, configuration.
绝对的，呃，配置是绝对的。
So what we could do is just, uh,
所以我们能做的就是，呃，
do a series of skewing, uh,
做一系列的歪斜，呃，
to to put it into the right, uh, configuration.
把它放到右边，呃，配置。
And this is, uh, yeah.
这是，呃，是的。
Just a, just a quick contrast to,
只是一个，只是一个快速对比，
to show, um, the difference in memory requirements.
显示，嗯，内存要求的差异。
So, er, a lot of the times the challenge is in, uh,
所以，呃，挑战的次数很多，呃，
being able to scale, uh, you know,
能够扩展，呃，你知道，
being able to be more memory efficient so that [NOISE] you can model longer sequences.
能够提高内存效率，以便[NOISE]可以模拟更长的序列。
So with that, uh, this is,
那么，呃，这是，
um, I can play you one more example if we have time.
嗯，如果我们有时间，我可以再给你一个例子。
But if we don't have time, we can, go ahead.
但如果我们没有时间，我们可以继续。
We'll see more of that.
我们会看到更多。
Okay. [LAUGHTER] So this is,
好的。 [大笑]所以这是，
this is, uh, maybe a one, uh,
这是，呃，也许是一个，呃，
about a one-minute sample and I- I hope you like it.
大约一分钟的样品和我 - 我希望你喜欢它。
Thanks. [MUSIC]
谢谢。 [音乐]
Thank you for listening.
谢谢你的收听。
[APPLAUSE].
[掌声]。
[LAUGHTER] Thanks, Anna. Um, um, great.
[大笑]谢谢，安娜。恩，嗯，太棒了。
Um, so to sort to, um,
嗯，好吧，嗯，
so relative attention has been a powerful mechanism for,
所以相对注意力是一种强大的机制，
um, a very powerful mechanism for music.
嗯，一个非常强大的音乐机制。
It's also helped in machine translation.
它也有助于机器翻译。
Um, one really interesting, uh,
嗯，一个非常有趣，呃，
consequences of, uh, of, um,
嗯，嗯，嗯，
one really interesting consequence of relative attention in,
相对关注的一个非常有趣的结果，
uh, images, is that,
呃，图像，是的，
um, like convolutions achieve,
嗯，就像卷积实现一样，
uh, convolutions achieve translational equivariance.
呃，卷积实现平移等价。
So if you have,
所以，如果你有，
let's say, you wa- uh, you have this,
让我们说，你好，你有这个，
this red dot or this feature that you're computing at this red dot,
这个红点或你在这个红点上计算的这个特征，
it doesn't depend on where the image of the dog is in the image,
它不取决于狗的图像在图像中的位置，
is in the the larger image. It just doesn't depend on its absolute location.
是在更大的图像。它只是不依赖于它的绝对位置。
It's going to, it's going to produce the same activation.
它会发生，它将产生相同的激活。
So you have- convolutions have this nice, uh, translation equivariance.
所以你有 - 卷积有这个很好的，呃，翻译等价。
Now, with, with relative,
现在，和亲戚在一起
uh, positions or relative attention,
呃，职位或相对关注，
you get exactly the same effect because you don't have any- once you just
你会得到完全相同的效果，因为你没有任何 - 只要你一次
remove this notion of absolute position that you are injecting [NOISE] into the model,
删除你将[NOISE]注入模型的绝对位置概念，
uh, once you've, once you've removed that,
呃，一旦你去了，一旦你删除了，
then your attention computation,
然后你的注意力计算，
because it actually includes I mean, we've,
因为它实际上包括我的意思，我们已经，
we've- Niki and I couple of others have actually,
我们 - 尼基和我其他几个人实际上，
and Anna were actually working on images and seems-
和安娜实际上正在研究图像，似乎 -
and it seems to actually show, uh, better results.
它似乎实际上表明，呃，更好的结果。
Um, this actio- this now satisfies this,
嗯，这个行动 - 这现在满足了这个，
uh, uh, the- I mean, it,
呃，呃，我的意思是，它，
it can achieve translation equivariance which is a great property for images.
它可以实现平移等价，这是图像的一个很好的属性。
So there's a lot of- it seems like this might be
所以有很多 - 似乎这可能是
an interesting direction to pursue if you want to push,
如果你想推动一个有趣的方向，
uh, Self-Attention in images for a self-supervised learning.
呃，自我注意图像中的自我监督学习。
Um, I guess on, on self-supervised learning so the geni- generative modeling work that,
嗯，我猜，关于自我监督的学习，所以生成建模工作，
that I talked about before in,
我之前谈过的，
in itself just having probabilistic models of images is, I mean,
我的意思是，本身只有图像的概率模型
I guess the best model of an image is I,
我想图像的最佳模型是我，
I go to Google search and I pick up an image and I just give it to you,
我去谷歌搜索，我拿起一张图片，我就把它给你，
but I guess generative models of images are useful because,
但我猜图像的生成模型是有用的，因为，
if you want to do something like semis-, uh, uh,
如果你想做一些像semis-，呃，呃，
self supervised learning where you just pre-train a model on
自我监督学习，你只是预先培训模型
a lot of- on a lot of unlabeled data then you transfer it.
很多未标记的数据然后你转移它。
So hopefully, this is gonna help and this is gonna be a part of that machinery.
所以希望，这会有所帮助，这将成为该机制的一部分。
Um, another interesting, uh,
嗯，另一个有趣的，呃，
another indus-interesting structure that relative attention allows you to model,
另一个行业有趣的结构，相对关注允许你建模，
is, uh, is, is kind of a graph.
呃，是，是一种图形。
So imagine you have this, uh,
所以想象你有这个，呃，
you have this similarity graph where these red edges are,
你有这个红色边缘的相似图，
are this notion of companies,
这是公司的概念，
and the blue edge is a notion of a fruit, uh,
蓝色的边缘是水果的概念，呃，
and um, an apple takes these two forms.
而嗯，苹果采用这两种形式。
And, uh, and you could just imagine
而且，呃，你可以想象
relative attention just modeling this- just being able to model,
相对注意只是建模这个 - 只是能够建模，
or being able to- you, you,
或者能够 - 你，你，
yourself being able to impose these different notions of similarity uh,
你自己能够强加这些不同的相似概念呃，
between, uh, between, uh, different elements.
之间，呃，之间，呃，不同的元素。
Uh, so if you have like, if you have graph problems, um,
呃，如果你有，如果你有图形问题，嗯，
then relative self-attention might be a good fit for you.
那么相对的自我关注可能非常适合你。
Um, there's also, there's also a simi- quite a position paper by Battaglia et al from
嗯，还有，Battaglia等人也提供了一份类似的立场文件
Deep Mind that talks about relative attention and how it can be used, um, within graphs.
深入思考，谈论相对关注以及如何在图表中使用它。
So while we're on graphs,
所以当我们在图上时，
I just wanted to- perhaps might be interesting to connect,
我只是想 - 也许可能有趣的连接，
um, uh, of- some, uh,
嗯，呃，有些，呃，
excellent work that was done on, uh,
做得很好的工作，呃，
on graphs called Message Passing Neural Networks.
在称为消息传递神经网络的图上。
And it's quite funny, so if you look at,
这很有趣，所以如果你看一下，
if you look at the message passing function, um,
如果你看一下消息传递函数，嗯，
what it's saying is you're actually just passing messages between pairs of nodes.
它的含义是你实际上只是在节点对之间传递消息。
So you can just think of self attention as imposing a fully connect- it's
因此，您可以将自我关注视为强加完全连接
like a bipe- a full, a complete bipartite graph,
像一个完整的，完整的二分图，
and, uh, you're, you're passing messages between,
而且，呃，你是，你在之间传递信息，
you're passing messages between nodes.
你在节点之间传递消息。
Now message passing, message passing neural networks did exactly that.
现在消息传递，消息传递神经网络正是这样做的。
They were passing messages between nodes as well. And how are they different?
他们也在节点之间传递消息。它们有何不同？
Well, the only way that when- well, mathematically,
嗯，这是唯一的方式 - 在数学上，
they were only different in that message passing was,
他们只是在传递信息方面不同​​，
was, uh, forcing the messages to be between pairs of nodes,
呃，迫使消息在节点对之间，
but just because of the Softmax function where you get interaction between all the nodes,
但正因为Softmax功能，您可以在所有节点之间进行交互，
self attention is like a message passing mechanism,
自我关注就像一个消息传递机制，
where the interactions are between all, all nodes.
所有节点之间的交互。
So, uh, they're, they're like,
那么，呃，他们是，他们就像，
they're not too far mathematically,
他们在数学上并不太远，
and also the me- the Message Passing Paper introduces
还有我 - 消息传递论文介绍
an interesting concept called Multiple Towers that are similar to multi-head attention,
一个名为Multiple Towers的有趣概念，类似于多头注意，
uh, that, that Norman invented.
呃，诺曼发明的那个。
And, uh, it's like you run k copies of these message passing neural networks in parallel.
而且，呃，就像你运行这些消息的k个副本并行通过神经网络。
So there's a lot of similarity between existing, you know,
所以，现有的，你知道，有很多相似之处，
this connects to work that existed before but these connections sort of came in later.
这连接到之前存在的工作，但这些连接后来出现了。
Um, we have a graph library where we kind of connected these both,
嗯，我们有一个图库，我们将它们连接起来，
both these strands message passing and, uh, we,
这两股消息传递，呃，我们，
uh, we put it out in tensor2tensor.
呃，我们把它放在tensor2tensor中。
Um, so to sort of summarize, um,
嗯，总结一下，嗯，
the properties that Self-Attention has been able to help
自我关注能够提供帮助的属性
us model is this constant path length between any two,
我们的模型是任何两个之间的恒定路径长度，
any two positions, and it's been,
任何两个职位，它一直是，
it's been shown to be quite useful in,
它被证明是非常有用的，
in, in, uh, in sequence modeling.
in，in，呃，在序列建模中。
This advantage of having unbounded memory not having to pack information in finite,
这种无限内存的优点是不必在有限的情况下打包信息，
in, in sort of a finite amount of- in a,
in，在某种有限数量的中，
in a fixed amount of space,
在固定的空间内，
uh, where in, in our case our memory essentially grows with the sequences is,
呃，在我们的情况下，我们的记忆基本上随着序列而增长，
is helps you computationally, uh, it's trivial to parallelize.
是帮助你计算，呃，并行化是微不足道的。
You can, you can crunch a lot of data, it's uh,
你可以，你可以处理很多数据，呃，
which is useful if you wanna have your large data sets.
如果您想拥有大型数据集，这非常有用。
We found that it can model Self-Similarity.
我们发现它可以模拟自相似性。
Uh, It seems to be a very natural thing, uh,
呃，这似乎很自然，呃，
a very, a very natural phenomenon if you're dealing with images or music.
如果你正在处理图像或音乐，这是一种非常自然的现象。
Also, relative attention allows you to sort of, gives you this added dimension
此外，相对关注允许您排序，给你这个增加的维度
of being able to model expressive timing and music,
能够模仿表达时间和音乐，
well, this translational equivariance,
好吧，这个平移等价，
uh, it extends naturally to graphs.
呃，它自然地延伸到图表。
Um, so this part or everything that I talked so far was about sort of parallel training.
嗯，所以到目前为止我谈到的这部分或者所有内容都是关于平行训练的。
Um, so there's a very active area of research now using the Self-Attention models for,
嗯，现在有一个非常活跃的研究领域，现在使用Self-Attention模型，
for, for less auto-regressive generation.
对于较少的自回归生成。
So notice a- at generation time,
所以请注意 - 在世代时间，
notice that the decoder mask was causal,
注意解码器掩码是因果关系，
we couldn't look into the future.
我们无法展望未来。
So when we're, when we're generating we're still
所以，当我们生成时，我们仍在生产
generating sequentially left to right on the target side.
在目标侧从左到右依次生成。
Um, so, um, and, and,
嗯，嗯，和，和，
and, and why, why is generation hard?
而且，为什么，为什么一代人很难？
Well, because your outputs are multi-modal.
好吧，因为你的输出是多模态的。
I f you had- if you want to translate English to German,
我有你 - 如果你想把英语翻译成德语，
there's multiple ways and,
有多种方式，
and, and your, your second word that you're translating will depend on the first word.
而且，你正在翻译的第二个词将取决于第一个词。
For example, if you, if you first- the first word that you predict was danke,
例如，如果你，如果你是第一个 - 你预测的第一个词是danke，
then that's going to change the second word that you predict.
那会改变你预测的第二个词。
And if you just predicted them independently,
如果你只是独立预测它们，
then you can imagine you can just have all sorts of
那么你可以想象你可以拥有各种各样的东西
permutations of these which will be incorrect.
这些的排列是不正确的。
Uh, and the way we actually break modes is
呃，我们实际打破模式的方式是
just- or we make decisions is just sequential generation.
只是 - 或者我们做出决定只是顺序生成。
Once we commit to a word that makes a decision,
一旦我们承诺做出决定，
and then that nails down what's the next word that you're going to predict.
然后指出你将要预测的下一个词是什么。
So there's been some, there's been some work on, it's an active research area, uh,
所以有一些，有一些工作，这是一个活跃的研究领域，呃，
and you can kind of categorize some of these papers like
你可以对这些论文中的一些进行分类
the non-autogressive transformer of the fast- the third paper, fast decoding.
快速的第三篇论文的非渐进式变换器，快速解码。
Um, the fourth paper towards a better understanding
嗯，第四篇有助于更好理解的论文
of all Vector Quantized Auto-encoders into this group,
所有矢量量化自动编码器进入该组，
where they're actually make- doing the decision making in a latent space,
实际上他们在潜在的空间做决策，
that's being, uh, it's e- either being learned using word alignments,
是的，呃，这是e-要么是使用单词对齐来学习的，
uh, fertilities, or that's being learned using Auto-encoders.
呃，这些或者是使用自动编码器学习的。
So you make- you do the decision making in latent space,
所以你做 - 你在潜在空间做决策，
and then you- once you've made the decisions in latent space,
然后你 - 一旦你在潜伏的空间做出决定，
you assume that all your outputs,
你假设你的所有输出，
are actually conditionally independent,
实际上是条件独立的
given that you've made these decisions.
鉴于你做出了这些决定。
So that's how they actually speed up.
这就是他们实际加速的方式。
There's also- there's ano- there's another paper.
还有 - 还有另一篇论文。
The second one is a
第二个是
paper that does Iterative Refinement.
做迭代细化的论文。
There is also a Blockwise Parallel Decoding paper by Mitchell Stern,
米切尔斯特恩还有一个Blockwise Parallel Decoding论文，
uh, Noam Shazeer, and Jakob Uszkoreit, uh,
呃，Noam Shazeer和Jakob Uszkoreit，呃，
where they essentially just run multiple models like, uh,
他们基本上只运行多个模型，呃，
and rescore using a more- a decode using a faster model and score,
并使用更快的模型和分数使用更多解码，
using the more expensive model.
使用更昂贵的模型。
So that's how it sort of it speeds it up.
这就是它如何加快速度。
Um, [NOISE] transfer learning has had the- Self-Attention has been beneficial in transfer
嗯，[NOISE]转移学习已经 - 自我注意在转移中是有益的
learning, GPT from OpenAI and BERT are two classic examples.
学习，OpenAI和BERT的GPT是两个经典的例子。
There's been some work on actually, scaling this up,
实际上有一些工作，扩大规模，
like add a factor as, uh, efficient optimizer.
喜欢添加一个因素，呃，高效的优化器。
Um, there's a, there's a recent paper by Rohan Anil and Yoram Singer.
嗯，还有一个，Rohan Anil和Yoram Singer最近发表了一篇论文。
Um, there's also Mesh-Tensorflow,
嗯，还有Mesh-Tensorflow，
which actually they've been able to train models
实际上他们已经能够训练模型了
of just several orders of magnitude larger than the original models have been trained.
仅比原始模型大几个数量级的训练。
So there's, I mean, when you're working this large data regime you would probably want to
所以，我的意思是，当你正在使用这种大数据制度时，你可能会想要
memorize a lot of- you want to memorize
记住很多 - 你想记住
a lot of things inside your parameters used to train a larger model.
你的参数中有很多东西用来训练一个更大的模型。
Uh, Mesh-Tensorflow can uh, can let you do that.
呃，Mesh-Tensorflow可以，呃，可以让你这样做。
Um, there has been a lot of interesting work, universal transformers,
嗯，有很多有趣的工作，通用变压器，
sort of recurrent neural networks can actually count very nicely.
一种反复出现的神经网络实际上可以非常好地计算。
There's these cute papers by Schmidhuber where he actually shows
Schmidhuber有这些可爱的论文，他实际上是在那里展示的
that recurring neural, the count- the cell mechanism just learns a nice counter,
那个反复发生的神经，计数 - 细胞机制才能学会一个好的计数器，
like if you're- you can learn kind of a to the n,
就像你 - 你可以学到一种对n，
b to the n, uh, with LSTM.
b到n，呃，用LSTM。
So then, uh, universals transformers
那么，呃，普遍变形金刚
brings back recurrence in depth inside the transformer.
带回变压器内部的深度重现。
Uh, there is a really cool Wikipedia paper,
呃，有一篇很酷的维基百科论文，
um, simultaneously with the image transformer paper that also uses local attention.
嗯，与图像变压器纸同时使用本地注意力。
Transformer-XL paper that sort of combines recurrence with Self-Attention,
Transformer-XL纸张将复发与自我注意结合起来，
so they do Self-Attention in chunks,
所以他们一块一块地自我注意，
but they sort of summarize history by using recurrence, it's kinda cute.
但他们通过使用复发来总结历史，它有点可爱。
It's been used in speech but I don't know if there's been
它已被用于演讲，但我不知道是否有过
some fairly big success stories of Self-Attention in speech.
演讲中自我注意的一些相当大的成功故事。
Uh, again, similar issues where you have very large, uh,
呃，再次，你有很大的类似问题，呃，
um as positions to,
作为职位，
uh, to do Self-Attention over.
呃，要自我注意。
So yeah, um, self supervision is a- if it works it would be,
所以，是的，嗯，自我监督是 - 如果它有效，那将是，
it would be, it would be very beneficial.
它会，这将是非常有益的。
We wouldn't need large label datasets, understanding transfer,
我们不需要大型标签数据集，了解转移，
transfers is becoming very succe- becoming- is becoming
转移正在变得非常成功
a reality in NLP with BERT and some of these other models.
与BERT和其他一些模型在NLP中的现实。
So understanding how these, what's actually happening is a-
因此，了解这些，实际发生的是 -
is an interesting area of ongoing research for me and a couple.
对我和一对夫妇来说，这是一个有趣的研究领域。
And a few of my collaborators and uh, multitask learning and surmounting this,
还有一些我的合作者和呃，多任务学习和超越这个，
this quadratic problem with Self-Attention is
这种自我注意的二次问题是
an interesting area of research that I- that I'd like to pursue. Thank you.
我想要研究的一个有趣的研究领域。谢谢。